RESEARCH INTEREST

I'm interested in applying computational methods to address pitfalls and safeguards in online political communication. My most recent studies focus on fake news including 1) examine to what extent different ground truth labels impact downstream analysis, 2) evaluate biases in existing fake news models, and 3) explore methods that can effectively curtail fake news. My other ongoing projects include studying online movements, protest strategies, and outcomes.

My primary research methods include network analysis, natural language processing, machine learning, data scraping and storage, data visualization, statistics, web services, and crowdsourcing (e.g., Mechanical Turk).

EDUCATION

| PhD. | Information School, University of Michigan | Sep 2016- Current |
|------|--------------------------------------------|--------------------|
| B.S. | Computer Science, University of Washington | Sep 2009- Dec 2012 |

RESEARCH & WORK HISTORY

| • | PhD Research Intern | Microsoft Research, India | May - Aug 2018 |
|---|---------------------|------------------------------------|---------------------|
| • | Visiting Researcher | University of Washington, Seattle | Aug 2015 - Jan 2016 |
| • | Software Engineer | Google Inc., Social Infrastructure | Jun 2014 - Feb 2016 |
| • | Software Engineer | Amazon Inc., External Payments | Feb 2013 – Jun 2014 |
| • | SDE Intern | Expedia Inc., Orders | Jun 2012 – Sep 2012 |

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-reviewed Conference and Journal Papers

- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Market Forces: Quantifying the Role of Top Credible Ad Servers in the Fake News Ecosystem", forthcoming, ICWSM (2021)
- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Beyond the Eye-Catchers: a Large-Scale Study of Social Movement Organizations' Involvement in Online Protests". New Media & Society (2020)
- Lia Bozarth, Anmol Panda, Joyojeet Pal, "From Greetings to Corruption: Politicians, Political Parties, and Tweeting in India", ICTD (2020).
- Lia Bozarth, Aparajita Saraf, and Ceren Budak, "Higher Ground? How Groundtruth Labeling Impacts Our Understanding of the Spread of Fake News During the 2016 Election", ICWSM(2020).
- Lia Bozarth and Ceren Budak "Toward a Systematic Evaluation Framework of Fake News Classifiers", ICWSM(2020).
- Lia Bozarth & Joyojeet Pal, "Twitter Discourse as a Lens into Politicians' Interest in Technology and Development", in proceedings, ICTDX (2018).
- Lia Bozarth & Ceren Budak, "Is Slacktivism Underrated? Measuring the Value of Slacktivists for Online Social Movements", in proceedings, ICWSM (2017).

Non-archival Papers

- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Market Forces: Quantifying the Role of Top Credible Ad Servers in the Fake News Ecosystem", IC2S2 (2020)
- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Measuring Ideological Bias in Fake News Classifiers", IC2S2 (2020)

AWARDS, ARTICLES & IN THE PRESS:

- Robert Bond, Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, Kelly Garrett, Jason Jones, Drew Margolin, "The Case for Studying Obscure Falsehoods", forthcoming, Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review (2021)
- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "Profit for You and Me: Exploring Ad Servers on Fake News Sites", best poster for the category "Most Likely to Make a Societal Impact", MIDAS Data Symposium (2019)
- Lia Bozarth, Ceren Budak, "A Large-scale Study of Social Movement Organizations (SMOs) in Online Movements", best poster honorable mention, MIDAS TweetCon (2019)
- Joyojeet Pal & Lia Bozarth, "How Modi lost his mojo and Rahul roared to life on Twitter", Quartz (2018).
- Joyojeet Pal & Lia Bozarth, "Is Tweeting in Indian Languages Helping Politicians Widen Their Reach?", Economic and Political Weekly (2018).

ACADEMIC SERVICE:

- Graduate Student Instructor (GSI) at the University of Michigan
- Coordinator for Computational Social Science Methods (CSSM) Reading Group
- Student Representative at Rackham Graduate Student Government